[
    {
        "question": "\u201cHear this word, you cows of Bashan, who are on the mountain of Samaria, who oppress the poor, who crush the needy, who say to your husbands, \u2018Bring, that we may drink!\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:1",
        "rank": "700"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFor the Lord GOD does nothing without revealing his secret to his servants the prophets. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:7",
        "rank": "822"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, the days are coming,\u201d declares the Lord GOD, \u201cwhen I will send a famine on the land\u2014 not a famine of bread, nor a thirst for water, but of hearing the words of the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 8:11",
        "rank": "829"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cDo two walk together, unless they have agreed to meet? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:3",
        "rank": "1,304"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cIn that day I will raise up the booth of David that is fallen and repair its breaches, and raise up its ruins and rebuild it as in the days of old, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 9:11",
        "rank": "1,397"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore thus says the LORD: \u201c\u2018Your wife shall be a prostitute in the city, and your sons and your daughters shall fall by the sword, and your land shall be divided up with a measuring line; you yourself shall die in an unclean land, and Israel shall surely go into exile away from its land.\u2019\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 7:17",
        "rank": "1,755"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI hate, I despise your feasts, and I take no delight in your solemn assemblies. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:21",
        "rank": "1,900"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a lion roar in the forest, when he has no prey? Does a young lion cry out from his den, if he has taken nothing? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:4",
        "rank": "1,992"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he said: \u201cThe LORD roars from Zion and utters his voice from Jerusalem; the pastures of the shepherds mourn, and the top of Carmel withers.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:2",
        "rank": "2,462"
    },
    {
        "question": "Woe to you who desire the day of the LORD! Why would you have the day of the LORD? It is darkness, and not light, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:18",
        "rank": "2,594"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is a trumpet blown in a city, and the people are not afraid? Does disaster come to a city, unless the LORD has done it? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:6",
        "rank": "2,595"
    },
    {
        "question": "All the sinners of my people shall die by the sword, who say, \u2018Disaster shall not overtake or meet us.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 9:10",
        "rank": "2,629"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon the house of Hazael, and it shall devour the strongholds of Ben-hadad. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:4",
        "rank": "2,900"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYou only have I known of all the families of the earth; therefore I will punish you for all your iniquities. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:2",
        "rank": "2,939"
    },
    {
        "question": "The words of Amos, who was among the shepherds(1) of Tekoa, which he saw concerning Israel in the days of Uzziah king of Judah and in the days of Jeroboam the son of Joash, king of Israel, two years(2) before the earthquake. Footnotes (1) 1:1 Or *sheep breeders* (2) 1:1 Or *during two years* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:1",
        "rank": "3,014"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cWoe to those who are at ease in Zion, and to those who feel secure on the mountain of Samaria, the notable men of the first of the nations, to whom the house of Israel comes! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:1",
        "rank": "3,056"
    },
    {
        "question": "But let justice roll down like waters, and righteousness like an ever-flowing stream. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:24",
        "rank": "3,106"
    },
    {
        "question": "Does a bird fall in a snare on the earth, when there is no trap for it? Does a snare spring up from the ground, when it has taken nothing? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:5",
        "rank": "3,214"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the LORD said to me, \u201cAmos, what do you see?\u201d And I said, \u201cA plumb line.\u201d Then the Lord said, \u201cBehold, I am setting a plumb line in the midst of my people Israel; I will never again pass by them; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 7:8",
        "rank": "3,394"
    },
    {
        "question": "O you who turn justice to wormwood(1) and cast down righteousness to the earth! Footnotes (1) 5:7 Or *to bitter fruit* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:7",
        "rank": "3,427"
    },
    {
        "question": "offer a sacrifice of thanksgiving of that which is leavened, and proclaim freewill offerings, publish them; for so you love to do, O people of Israel!\u201d declares the Lord GOD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:5",
        "rank": "3,513"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Gaza, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because they carried into exile a whole people to deliver them up to Edom. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:6",
        "rank": "3,523"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon the wall of Gaza, and it shall devour her strongholds. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:7",
        "rank": "3,781"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore they shall now be the first of those who go into exile, and the revelry of those who stretch themselves out shall pass away.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:7",
        "rank": "3,796"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Tyre, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because they delivered up a whole people to Edom, and did not remember the covenant of brotherhood. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:9",
        "rank": "3,829"
    },
    {
        "question": "the high places of Isaac shall be made desolate, and the sanctuaries of Israel shall be laid waste, and I will rise against the house of Jeroboam with the sword.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 7:9",
        "rank": "3,857"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will cut off the ruler from its midst, and will kill all its princes(1) with him,\u201d says the LORD. Footnotes (1) 2:3 Or *officials* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:3",
        "rank": "3,948"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will cut off the inhabitants from Ashdod, and him who holds the scepter from Ashkelon; I will turn my hand against Ekron, and the remnant of the Philistines shall perish,\u201d says the Lord GOD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:8",
        "rank": "3,962"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Edom, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because he pursued his brother with the sword and cast off all pity, and his anger tore perpetually, and he kept his wrath forever. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:11",
        "rank": "4,052"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon the wall of Tyre, and it shall devour her strongholds.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:10",
        "rank": "4,053"
    },
    {
        "question": "and their king shall go into exile, he and his princes(1) together,\u201d says the LORD. Footnotes (1) 1:15 Or *officials* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:15",
        "rank": "4,105"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will turn your feasts into mourning and all your songs into lamentation; I will bring sackcloth on every waist and baldness on every head; I will make it like the mourning for an only son and the end of it like a bitter day. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 8:10",
        "rank": "4,166"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will kindle a fire in the wall of Rabbah, and it shall devour her strongholds, with shouting on the day of battle, with a tempest in the day of the whirlwind; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:14",
        "rank": "4,269"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon Teman, and it shall devour the strongholds of Bozrah.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:12",
        "rank": "4,365"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of the Ammonites, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because they have ripped open pregnant women in Gilead, that they might enlarge their border. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:13",
        "rank": "4,383"
    },
    {
        "question": "And if ten men remain in one house, they shall die. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:9",
        "rank": "4,471"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then Amaziah the priest of Bethel sent a message to Jeroboam king of Israel: \"Amos is raising a conspiracy against you in the very heart of Israel. The land cannot bear all his words.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 7:10",
        "rank": "4,541"
    },
    {
        "question": "He flashes destruction on the stronghold and brings the fortified city to ruin.",
        "answer": "Amos 5:9",
        "rank": "4,721"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then Amaziah said to Amos, \"Get out, you seer! Go back to the land of Judah. Earn your bread there and do your prophesying there.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 7:12",
        "rank": "4,751"
    },
    {
        "question": "So that they may possess the remnant of Edom and all the nations that bear my name,\" declares the LORD, who will do these things.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 9:12",
        "rank": "4,843"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Judah, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because they have rejected the law of the LORD, and have not kept his statutes, but their lies have led them astray, those after which their fathers walked. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:4",
        "rank": "4,844"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord GOD has sworn by himself, declares the LORD, the God of hosts: \u201cI abhor the pride of Jacob and hate his strongholds, and I will deliver up the city and all that is in it.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:8",
        "rank": "4,870"
    },
    {
        "question": "The lion has roared; who will not fear? The Lord GOD has spoken; who can but prophesy?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:8",
        "rank": "5,106"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI also withheld the rain from you when there were yet three months to the harvest; I would send rain on one city, and send no rain on another city; one field would have rain, and the field on which it did not rain would wither; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:7",
        "rank": "5,122"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore because you trample on(1) the poor and you exact taxes of grain from him, you have built houses of hewn stone, but you shall not dwell in them; you have planted pleasant vineyards, but you shall not drink their wine. Footnotes (1) 5:11 Or *you tax* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:11",
        "rank": "5,163"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hear this word that I take up over you in lamentation, O house of Israel: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:1",
        "rank": "5,645"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Don't prophesy anymore at Bethel, because this is the king's sanctuary and the temple of the kingdom.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 7:13",
        "rank": "5,710"
    },
    {
        "question": "For thus Amos has said, \u201c\u2018Jeroboam shall die by the sword, and Israel must go into exile away from his land.\u2019\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 7:11",
        "rank": "5,863"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon Judah, and it shall devour the strongholds of Jerusalem.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:5",
        "rank": "5,995"
    },
    {
        "question": "Proclaim to the strongholds in Ashdod and to the strongholds in the land of Egypt, and say, \u201cAssemble yourselves on the mountains of Samaria, and see the great tumults within her, and the oppressed in her midst.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:9",
        "rank": "6,055"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cAs the shepherd rescues from the mouth of the lion two legs, or a piece of an ear, so shall the people of Israel who dwell in Samaria be rescued, with the corner of a couch and part(1) of a bed. Footnotes (1) 3:12 The meaning of the Hebrew word is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:12",
        "rank": "6,095"
    },
    {
        "question": "those who trample the head of the poor into the dust of the earth and turn aside the way of the afflicted; a man and his father go in to the same girl, so that my holy name is profaned; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:7",
        "rank": "6,183"
    },
    {
        "question": "For I know how many are your transgressions and how great are your sins\u2014 you who afflict the righteous, who take a bribe, and turn aside the needy in the gate. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:12",
        "rank": "6,249"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI struck you with blight and mildew; your many gardens and your vineyards, your fig trees and your olive trees the locust devoured; yet you did not return to me,\u201d declares the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:9",
        "rank": "6,250"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore thus says the LORD, the God of hosts, the Lord: \u201cIn all the squares there shall be wailing, and in all the streets they shall say, \u2018Alas! Alas!\u2019 They shall call the farmers to mourning and to wailing those who are skilled in lamentation, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:16",
        "rank": "6,261"
    },
    {
        "question": "They shall wander from sea to sea, and from north to east; they shall run to and fro, to seek the word of the LORD, but they shall not find it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 8:12",
        "rank": "6,323"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will plant them on their land, and they shall never again be uprooted out of the land that I have given them,\u201d says the LORD your God. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 9:15",
        "rank": "6,358"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore thus says the Lord GOD: \u201cAn adversary shall surround the land and bring down(1) your defenses from you, and your strongholds shall be plundered.\u201d Footnotes (1) 3:11 Hebrew *An adversary, one who surrounds the land\u2014he shall bring down* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:11",
        "rank": "6,458"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThey do not know how to do right,\u201d declares the LORD, \u201cthose who store up violence and robbery in their strongholds.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:10",
        "rank": "6,544"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYet it was I who destroyed the Amorite before them, whose height was like the height of the cedars and who was as strong as the oaks; I destroyed his fruit above and his roots beneath. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:9",
        "rank": "6,545"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI overthrew some of you, as when God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah, and you were as a brand(1) plucked out of the burning; yet you did not return to me,\u201d declares the LORD. Footnotes (1) 4:11 That is, a burning stick (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:11",
        "rank": "6,577"
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who swear by the Guilt of Samaria, and say, \u2018As your god lives, O Dan,\u2019 and, \u2018As the Way of Beersheba lives,\u2019 they shall fall, and never rise again.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 8:14",
        "rank": "6,592"
    },
    {
        "question": "and in all vineyards there shall be wailing, for I will pass through your midst,\u201d says the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:17",
        "rank": "6,705"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will strike the winter house along with the summer house, and the houses of ivory shall perish, and the great houses(1) shall come to an end,\u201d declares the LORD. Footnotes (1) 3:15 Or *and many houses* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:15",
        "rank": "6,706"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore he who is prudent will keep silent in such a time, for it is an evil time. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:13",
        "rank": "6,749"
    },
    {
        "question": "And if the relative who comes to carry the bodies out of the house to burn them asks anyone who might be hiding there, \"Is anyone else with you?\" and he says, \"No,\" then he will go on to say, \"Hush! We must not mention the name of the LORD.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 6:10",
        "rank": "6,822"
    },
    {
        "question": "They lie down beside every altar on garments taken in pledge. In the house of their god they drink wine taken as fines.",
        "answer": "Amos 2:8",
        "rank": "6,853"
    },
    {
        "question": "People staggered from town to town for water but did not get enough to drink, yet you have not returned to me,\" declares the LORD.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 4:8",
        "rank": "7,033"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"In that day \"the lovely young women and strong young men will faint because of thirst.",
        "answer": "Amos 8:13",
        "rank": "7,260"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Did you bring me sacrifices and offerings forty years in the wilderness, house of Israel?\"",
        "answer": "Amos 5:25",
        "rank": "7,352"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the LORD took me from tending the flock and said to me, 'Go, prophesy to my people Israel.'",
        "answer": "Amos 7:15",
        "rank": "7,426"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"On the day I punish Israel for her sins, I will destroy the altars of Bethel; the horns of the altar will be cut off and fall to the ground.\"",
        "answer": "Amos 3:14",
        "rank": "7,541"
    },
    {
        "question": "I brought you up out of Egypt and led you forty years in the wilderness to give you the land of the Amorites.",
        "answer": "Amos 2:10",
        "rank": "7,566"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I sent plagues among you as I did to Egypt. I killed your young men with the sword, along with your captured horses. I filled your nostrils with the stench of your camps, yet you have not returned to me,\" declares the LORD.",
        "answer": "Amos 4:10",
        "rank": "7,594"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Are not you Israelites the same to me as the Cushites?\" declares the LORD. \"Did I not bring Israel up from Egypt, the Philistines from Caphtor and the Arameans from Kir?\"",
        "answer": "Amos 9:7",
        "rank": "7,623"
    },
    {
        "question": "This is what the LORD says: \"For three sins of Moab, even for four, I will not turn back my wrath. Because he burned to lime the bones of Edom's king,\"",
        "answer": "Amos 2:1",
        "rank": "7,713"
    },
    {
        "question": "For behold, the LORD commands, and the great house shall be struck down into fragments, and the little house into bits. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:11",
        "rank": "7,875"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I raised up some of your sons for prophets, and some of your young men for Nazirites. Is it not indeed so, O people of Israel?\u201d declares the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:11",
        "rank": "7,876"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBut you made the Nazirites drink wine, and commanded the prophets, saying, \u2018You shall not prophesy.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:12",
        "rank": "8,057"
    },
    {
        "question": "O you who put far away the day of disaster and bring near the seat of violence? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:3",
        "rank": "8,112"
    },
    {
        "question": "For thus says the LORD to the house of Israel: \u201cSeek me and live; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:4",
        "rank": "8,113"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cHear, and testify against the house of Jacob,\u201d declares the Lord GOD, the God of hosts, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 3:13",
        "rank": "8,114"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do horses run on rocks? Does one plow there(1) with oxen? But you have turned justice into poison and the fruit of righteousness into wormwood(2)\u2014 Footnotes (1) 6:12 Or *the sea* (2) 6:12 Or *into bitter fruit* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:12",
        "rank": "8,228"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cWoe to those who lie on beds of ivory and stretch themselves out on their couches, and eat lambs from the flock and calves from the midst of the stall, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:4",
        "rank": "8,332"
    },
    {
        "question": "Take away from me the noise of your songs; to the melody of your harps I will not listen. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:23",
        "rank": "8,437"
    },
    {
        "question": "but do not seek Bethel, and do not enter into Gilgal or cross over to Beersheba; for Gilgal shall surely go into exile, and Bethel shall come to nothing.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:5",
        "rank": "8,438"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now therefore hear the word of the LORD. \u201cYou say, \u2018Do not prophesy against Israel, and do not preach against the house of Isaac.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 7:16",
        "rank": "8,529"
    },
    {
        "question": "you who rejoice in Lo-debar,(1) who say, \u201cHave we not by our own strength captured Karnaim(2) for ourselves?\u201d Footnotes (1) 6:13 *Lo-debar* means *nothing* (2) 6:13 *Karnaim* means *horns* (a symbol of strength) (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:13",
        "rank": "8,574"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Israel, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment, because they sell the righteous for silver, and the needy for a pair of sandals\u2014 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:6",
        "rank": "8,603"
    },
    {
        "question": "as if a man fled from a lion, and a bear met him, or went into the house and leaned his hand against the wall, and a serpent bit him. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:19",
        "rank": "8,672"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFallen, no more to rise, is the virgin Israel; forsaken on her land, with none to raise her up.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:2",
        "rank": "8,784"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is not the day of the LORD darkness, and not light, and gloom with no brightness in it? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:20",
        "rank": "8,936"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord GOD has sworn by his holiness that, behold, the days are coming upon you, when they shall take you away with hooks, even the last of you with fishhooks. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 4:2",
        "rank": "9,018"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFor behold, I will raise up against you a nation, O house of Israel,\u201d declares the LORD, the God of hosts; \u201cand they shall oppress you from Lebo-hamath to the Brook of the Arabah.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 6:14",
        "rank": "9,055"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, I will press you down in your place, as a cart full of sheaves presses down. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:13",
        "rank": "9,210"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cFor three transgressions of Damascus, and for four, I will not revoke the punishment,(1) because they have threshed Gilead with threshing sledges of iron. Footnotes (1) 1:3 Hebrew *I will not turn it back*; also verses 6, 9, 11, 13 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 1:3",
        "rank": "9,211"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I will send a fire upon Moab, and it shall devour the strongholds of Kerioth, and Moab shall die amid uproar, amid shouting and the sound of the trumpet; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:2",
        "rank": "9,381"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cIf they dig into Sheol, from there shall my hand take them; if they climb up to heaven, from there I will bring them down. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 9:2",
        "rank": "9,464"
    },
    {
        "question": "Even though you offer me your burnt offerings and grain offerings, I will not accept them; and the peace offerings of your fattened animals, I will not look upon them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 5:22",
        "rank": "9,613"
    },
    {
        "question": "Flight shall perish from the swift, and the strong shall not retain his strength, nor shall the mighty save his life; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Amos 2:14",
        "rank": "9,614"
    }
]